Daniel:
SO, I WENT FISHING THIS WEEKEND.
CAUGHT A HUGE STRIPED BASS.
THIS BIG.
[ LAUGHTER ]
WE'RE HAVING IT MOUNTED
IN MY OFFICE.
ISN'T THAT RIGHT,
MR. LEWICKI?
UH, WHATEVER
YOU SAY, DOC.
[ LAUGHTER ]
ALL RIGHT.
SO, EVEN IF MY SOON-TO-BE
FORMER TEACHING ASSISTANT
DIDN'T ROLL OVER ON ME
LIKE A RAT IN A BAD MAFIA FLICK,
YOU'D KNOW I WAS LYING.
WHY?
'CAUSE IT'S A FISH STORY.
BUT IF I WAS A BETTER LIAR,
I'D HAVE A HUGE ADVANTAGE.
STUDIES SHOW THE MOST CONVINCING
LIARS LAND THE BEST JOBS,
MAKE THE MOST FRIENDS,
AND GET ALL THE HOT WOMEN.
SO IF I WAS REALLY GOOD AT IT,
WOULD THERE STILL BE A WAY
FOR YOU TO BUST ME?
A POLYGRAPH, MAYBE.
[ BEEPING ]
Kate: DID YOU DISCOVER
A MALE INTRUDER
IN YOUR HOME LAST NIGHT?
YES.
DO YOU KNOW THE IDENTITY
OF THIS MAN?
NO.
DID YOU SEE HIS FACE?
YES.
CAN YOU DESCRIBE IT?
NO.
A POLYGRAPH'S
NOT A BAD TOOL,
BUT IT ONLY MEASURES
STRESS RESPONSE.
IN THIS CLASS, WE'RE INTERESTED
IN WHAT GOES ON IN THE BRAIN.
AND IF WE WERE TO PUT SOMEONE
IN AN fMRI MACHINE
AND WATCH WHAT HAPPENS
WHEN THEY MAKE UP A LIE,
WE'D SEE THEIR DORSOLATERAL
PREFRONTAL CORTEX
LIGHT UP
LIKE A CHRISTMAS TREE...
[ LAUGHTER ]
...BECAUSE WE USE OUR BRAINS
WHEN WE LIE.
WE USE OUR BRAINS
WHEN WE'RE BEING LIED TO.
BUT...
CAN THE BRAIN
EVER LIE TO ITSELF?
Max: ALL RIGHT.
SO YOU'VE GOT OFFICE HOURS
FROM 1:00 TO 3:00,
AND DON'T FORGET
THE MEETING
WITH DEAN HALEY
AND THAT HATHAWAY GUY AT 4:00.
GET OH, OKAY. IT.
WHAT AM I
I DON'T KNOW.ELL HIM?
USE YOUR DORSOLATERAL
PREFRONTAL CORTEX AND
MAKE SOMETHING UP.
SO YOU WANT ME
TO LIE FOR YOU NOW?
THINK OF IT AS FOR WHAT?
FOR LANDING A NEW JOB
WHEN I FIRE YOU
FOR NOT GETTING ME OUT
OF THE MEETING WITH DEAN HALEY.
DOC, THAT DOESN'T
MAKE ANY SENSE.
IT'S A PARADOX, LEWICKI.
IT'S NOT SUPPOSED TO.
OH, GOD! I'M SO SORRY.
[ British accent ]
IN A BIT OF A HURRY, AREN'T WE?
I'M GONNA PAY FOR YOUR
DRY CLEANING, OKAY?
MY FAULT. I WASN'T
LOOKING WHERE I WAS GOING.
IN FACT, COULD WE PLEASE
MAKE THE LADY ANOTHER?
I INSIST.FINE.
[ SIGHS ]
CHAMOMILE TEA.
GOOD CHOICE.
I DON'T THINK YOU NEED
ANY MORE CAFFEINE.
ACTUALLY,
THE TEA IS FOR A FRIEND,
AND I CAN HANDLE MY CAFFEINE
JUST FINE.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
HOW ABOUT YOUR LIQUOR?
EXCUSE ME?
WELL, SEEING AS I'M
BUYING THE TEA,
I THOUGHT MAYBE
YOU COULD BUY ME A REAL DRINK.
7:00's GOOD FOR ME.
THANK YOU FOR THE TEA,
AND AGAIN, I'M VERY SORRY
ABOUT THE SHIRT.
Daniel: KATE.
WHAT, AM I ON SOME SORT
OF GOVERNMENT WATCH LIST?
NOT YET.
HERBAL TEA.
NO MILK, NO SUGAR.
NOW, I KNOW YOU DIDN'T
COME ALL THE WAY OVER HERE
JUST TO BRING ME TEA.
MEET FRANK
AND OLENA PRENTICE.
LOOKS LIKE
HE WON THE LOTTERY.
ACTUALLY,
SHE COST HIM A BUNDLE.
MAIL-ORDER BRIDE
FROM THE UKRAINE.
PEOPLE ACTUALLY
DO THAT?
YEAH. WHY? ARE YOU
IN THE MARKET FOR A WIFE?
NO.
"EASTERN BLOC
INTRODUCTIONS."
THEY ARRANGED FOR FRANK
TO FLY TO ODESSA
TO MEET WITH
PROSPECTIVE BRIDES.
BEFORE YOU KNOW IT,
WEDDING BELLS.
BUT FRANK HAS TO COME HOME WHILE
THEY WAIT FOR OLENA'S VISA.
IMMIGRATION PROBLEMS.
THEN HE GETS A CALL
FROM HER BROKER
SAYING IT'S GONNA BE
ANOTHER 100 GRAND
TO GET OLENA
INTO THE STATES.
NOW, FRANK DOESN'T HAVE
THAT KIND OF CASH.
SO THEN THE BROKER OFFERS HIM
ALTERNATIVE FINANCING.
CODE FOR "LOAN SHARK."
EXACTLY.
SO FRANK
GETS HIS NEW BRIDE,
BUT HE CAN'T KEEP UP
WITH THE PAYMENTS.
SO THEN THE LOAN SHARK
TELLS HIM
THAT THEY'RE GOING
TO TAKE OLENA AND MAKE
HER WORK OFF THE DEBT.
I'M GUESSING WE'RE NOT TALKING
ABOUT A NICE OFFICE JOB.
[ CHUCKLES ]
ALEXEI TUPELOV.
SUSPECTED OF RUNNING
THE LARGEST
PROSTITUTION AND LOAN-SHARKING
OPERATIONS IN THE MIDWEST.
THE BUREAU'S BEEN TRYING TO NAIL
THIS GUY FOR YEARS,
BUT NO ONE WILL TESTIFY.
HE ALSO HAPPENS TO OWN
EASTERN BLOC INTRODUCTIONS.
SO IT'S A FRONT COMYEAH.
WE THINK THAT THE LOAN SHARK'S
ONE OF TUPELOV'S BOYS,
AND LAST NIGHT HE MADE GOOD
ON HIS THREAT.
FRANK COMES HOME,
SEES A BLUE CAMARO
PARKED RIGHT OUTSIDE
HIS HOUSE.
HE GOES INSIDE.
THERE'S AN INTRUDER.
THEY FIGHT.
THE GUY SMASHES FRANK
OVER THE HEAD WITH A LAMP.
THE LIVE-IN MAID
COMES HOME FROM HER NIGHT OFF,
FINDS FRANK UNCONSCIOUS,
CALLS THE COPS,
BUT OLENA IS ALREADY GONE.
[ SCOFFS ] POOR GIRL.
YEAH.
HOW CAN I HELP?
HERE'S THE THING.
FRANK CAN'T GIVE US
A DESCRIPTION OF THIS GUY,
EVEN THOUGH
THEY WERE FACE TO FACE.
WELL, YOU SAID THE INTRUDER
HIT HIM OVER THE HEAD.
THAT COULD CERTAINLY
AFFECT HIS MEMORY.
THAT'S WHY
I BROUGHT THIS TO YOU.
FRANK'S MEMORY IS FINE.
HE CAN DESCRIBE
EVERYTHING
THAT HAPPENED LAST NIGHT
IN PERFECT DETAIL,
SO HOW IS IT THAT HE CAN'T TELL
US WHAT THIS GUY LOOKED LIKE?
[ BEEPING ]
WHAT THE [BLEEP]
IS THAT THING?
WHOLE-BODY-IMAGING
SCANNER.
IT WASN'T HERE
LAST TIME.
YEAH. NEW SECURITY PROTOCOLS.
I'LL MEET YOU ON THE OTHER SIDE.
[ BEEPING CONTINUES ]
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
[ CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYS ]
[ BEEPING INTENSIFIES ]
DANIEL!
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
DO YOU HAVE ANY IDEA THE
HEALTH RISKS THOSE THINGS POSE?
WH-- THAT?
THAT'S PERFECTLY SAFE.
According to who?
Some government regulatory body?
Like I really trust Uncle Sam
to look out for my well-being.
OKAY, LISTEN, WHAT EXACTLY IS IT
THAT YOU'RE AFRAID OF?
SKIN CANCER, THYROID DISEASE,
MUTATED SPERM.
M-MUTATED SPERM?
NOT TO MENTION
THE VIOLATION OF PRIVACY.
I'M NOT ABOUT TO LET
SOME $10-AN-HOUR RENT-A-COP
CHECK OUT
MY TESTICULAR REGION.
OKAY.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
WE'RE GONNA DO THIS
THE OLD-FASHIONED WAY.
YOU'RE REALLY ENJOYING THIS,
AREN'T YOU?
MR. PRENTICE,
YOU TOLD THE POLICE
THAT YOU STRUGGLED
WITH THE INTRUDER
FOR MORE THAN A MINUTE,
THAT YOU WERE FACE-TO-FACE
THE WHOLE TIME.
ANY DISTINGUISHING FEATURES
OR CHARACTERISTICS?
WELL, I TOLD THEM I'VE NEVER
BEEN TOO GOOD WITH FACES.
THE INTRUDER -- WAS IT THE SAME
MAN YOU'VE BEEN PAYING OFF?
MAYBE. WELL, THEY WERE
ABOUT THE SAME SIZE.
BUT THE GUY
THAT SHAKES ME DOWN
USUALLY WEARS ONE OF THOSE
ORTHODOX CROSSES --
A GOLD ONE ON A CHAIN
AROUND HIS NECK.
WHAT DOES YOUR WIFE
LOOK LIKE?
YOU GOT PICTURES OF HER.
WHAT DOES SHE LOOK LIKE
TO YOU?
BLOND, GOOD-LOOKING.
SHE GOT A GOOD BODY.
D-DO YOU REALLY THINK I'M GONNA
SPEND ALL THAT MONEY
TO BRING HER OVER HERE
IF SHE'S NOT HOT?
THE HUSBAND'S
A REAL CHARMER.
WE FIND THIS GIRL,
AND THEN WHAT?
SHE HAS TO GO BACK
TO THAT?
HERE.
PUT THIS ON.
JUST DO IT.
OKAY.
AND TAKE THESE.
WE'RE IN THE MIDDLE
OF AN INTERROGATION.
GO WITH ME ON THIS.
NOW, LET'S DO SOMETHING
ABOUT THAT HAIR.
FRANK, THIS IS MISS JONES.
SHE'S A SKETCH ARTIST.
SHE'S GONNA COME UP
WITH A COMPOSITE
OF THE MAN
WHO ATTACKED YOU.
I SURE AS [BLEEP] HOPE YOU'RE
MORE HELP THAN THAT LAST GIRL.
YOU DON'T RECOGNIZE HER?
WHY?
HAVE WE MET?
IT'S A SENSORY IMPAIRMENT
CALLED PROSOPAGNOSIA,
ALSO KNOWN AS
"FACE BLINDNESS."
EVEN THOUGH FRANK'S VISION
IS PERFECTLY NORMAL,
HE CAN'T RECOGNIZE FACES.
HE PROBABLY COULDN'T PICK
HIS OWN MOTHER OUT OF A LINEUP.
BECAUSE OF THE BLOW
TO THE HEAD?
IT CAN BE CAUSED BY DAMAGE
TO THE FUSIFORM GYRUS,
BUT FRANK SAID HE'D NEVER
BEEN GOOD WITH FACES,
WHICH MEANS
IT'S PROBABLY CONGENITAL.
WAIT A SECOND.
THIS GUY'S HAD THIS BIZARRO
CONDITION HIS ENTIRE LIFE,
AND HE DOESN'T KNOW IT?
HOW'S THAT EVEN POSSIBLE?
MOST PROSOPAGNOSIACS DEVELOP
UNCONSCIOUS STRATEGIES
FOR RECOGNIZING
THE PEOPLE THEY KNOW --
THE WAY THEY DRESS, THE CONTEXT
THEY SEE THEM IN, THEIR VOICE.
GREAT.
WELL, ACCORDING
TO FRANK'S STATEMENT,
THE INTRUDER NEVER SPOKE,
SO EVEN IF WE FIND THE GUY,
OUR WITNESS
CAN'T I.D. HIM.
FRANK SPOKE TO THE LOAN SHARK
AT LEAST HALF A DOZEN TIMES.
HE'D BE ABLE TO RECOGNIZE
HIS VOICE.
WE FIND THE LOAN SHARK, GET
DANIEL TO HELP FRANK I.D. HIM.
WE GRILL HIS SORRY [BLEEP] UNTIL
HE TELLS US WHERE OLENA IS.
CAN I GO NOW?
FRANK COULDN'T PICK ANYBODY
OUT OF THE PHOTO ARRAY.
HOW DO WE KNOW WHICH ONE
OF TUPELOV'S GUYS TO HAUL IN?
HOW ABOUT WE DROP OFF DANIEL
BACK AT CAMPUS
AND GO FIND YOU A WIFE?
WE KNOW THAT YOUR COMPANY
IS A FRONT FOR ALEXEI TUPELOV.
[ Slavic accent ]
HE'S AN INVESTOR. SO?
SO, YOU TWO ARE RUNNING
QUITE A SCAM --
RICH AMERICAN MEN
FOOT THE BILL
FOR PRETTY YOUNG GIRLS
TO EMIGRATE.
THEN YOU
SHAKE THE HUSBANDS DOWN.
AND IF THEY DON'T PAY,
YOU FORCE THEIR IMMIGRANT WIVES
INTO PROSTITUTION.
THAT'S RIDICULOUS.
OLENA PRENTICE --
ONE OF TUPELOV'S BOYS THREATENED
TO TAKE HER AS COLLATERAL,
AND NOW SHE'S MISSING.
THAT SOUNDS LIKE CONSPIRACY
TO COMMIT KIDNAPPING
AND EXTORTION TO ME.
DOES THAT SOUND LIKE EXTORTION
TO YOU, ROGER?
IT DOES,
AS A MATTER OF FACT.
I DON'T KNOW ANYTHING ABOUT
KIDNAPPING OR PROSTITUTION.
AND IF YOU ASK ME,
OLENA WENT BACK TO UKRAINE.
YOU THINK
SHE WENT HOME? WHY?
A FEW WEEKS
AFTER SHE GOT HERE,
SHE CALLED ME TO SAY
THAT FRANK WAS VERY MEAN TO HER.
HE DID NOT
LET HER LEAVE THE HOUSE.
SO SHE WANTED OUT.
SO YOU HELPED HER,
OF COURSE.
[ SIGHS ]
I'M A MARRIAGE BROKER,
NOT A MARRIAGE COUNSELOR.
I TOLD HER TO STICK IT OUT,
TO STAY A FEW YEARS,
THEN DIVORCE HIM,
TAKE HIS MONEY.
IT'S THE AMERICAN WAY,
RIGHT?
THERE IS AN INNOCENT YOUNG GIRL
MISSING WHO CAME TO THIS COUNTRY
TRYING TO MAKE A BETTER LIFE
FOR HERSELF.
YOU ARE RESPONSIBLE
FOR BRINGING HER HERE,
AND YOU COULDN'T BE BOTHERED
TO HELP HER WHEN SHE ASKED.
WHAT DO YOU WANT
FROM ME?
I WANT THE NAME OF THE MAN
WHO WAS SHAKING FRANK DOWN.
WHAT MAKES YOU THINK
THAT I --
IF YOU DON'T GIVE ME A NAME,
THIS PLACE IS GONNA BE SWARMING
WITH I.C.E. AGENTS,
U.S. ATTORNEYS, I.R.S.
YOU WILL GO TO FEDERAL PRISON,
KICKING YOURSELF
FOR NOT COOPERATING
WITH THAT NICE GIRL FROM THE FBI
WHEN YOU HAD THE CHANCE.
Kate:
YURI PETROVICH?
SPECIAL AGENT MORETTI,
FBI.
OH, FBI, HUH?
I MUST BE
MOVING UP IN THE WORLD.
WE'RE LOOKING FOR A MISSING
WOMAN -- OLENA PRENTICE.
I GOT ALL THE WOMEN I NEED
RIGHT HERE.
NEVER HEARD OF NO OLENA.
YEAH, THAT'S FUNNY,
BECAUSE YOU'VE BEEN SHAKING DOWN
HER HUSBAND, FRANK, THREATENING
TO TURN OUT HIS WIFE.
Roger: OKAY, THANKS.
A BODY MATCHING THE DESCRIPTION
OF OLENA PRENTICE
WAS JUST FOUND IN A LANDFILL
OUT BY MIDWAY.
CONGRATULATIONS, YURI.
YOU JUST BECAME
THE PRIME SUSPECT IN
A MURDER INVESTIGATION.
PAUL, YOU WANTED TO SEE --
DANIEL! PERFECT TIMING.
COME IN.
SAY HELLO
TO DR. MICHAEL HATHAWAY.
I'VE BEEN
TRYING TO CONVINCE MICHAEL
TO BRING HIS TALENTS
TO THE SOUTH SIDE
AND BECOME THE NEWEST MEMBER
OF OUR ESTEEMED FACULTY.
IT'S AN HONOR.
RIGHT.
YOU'RE THE, UH, FAMOUS
SELF-HELP SAGE TO THE STARS.
WELL, MY ACADEMIC SPECIALTY'S
BEHAVIORAL SCIENCE, OF COURSE.
THE "SAGE" PART
WAS MY PUBLICISTS' IDEA.
I FOUGHT THEM ON IT,
BUT IT MOVED SOME BOOKS,
SO WHAT DO I KNOW?
YOU KNOW, MICHAEL'S HAD
A NEW YORK TIMES BESTSELLER
THREE YEARS RUNNING.
IS THAT RIGHT?
I'VE READ ALL YOUR BOOKS.
YEAH, IN FACT,
WHEN PAUL RANG WITH HIS OFFER,
I SAID
I'D ONLY CONSIDER IT
IF IT MEANT A CHANCE
TO WORK WITH YOU.
UH, I READ
YOUR LAST BOOK, TOO.
IT WAS BRILLIANT...
W-WASN'T IT, DANIEL?
NO. NO.
I-I THOUGHT IT WAS A MUDDLED
MESS OF SHODDY RESEARCH,
JUNK SCIENCE,
AND PEDANTIC PLATITUDES,
BUT I HOPE YOU ENJOY
YOUR TIME IN CHICAGO.
IF YOU'LL EXCUSE ME, I HAVE SOME
ACTUAL SCHOLARSHIP TO ATTEND TO.
RIGHT.
[ CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYS ]
DOC.
OH, I WENT
TO THE [BLEEP] MEETING.
WHAT THE [BLEEP] ELSE
DO YOU WANT FROM ME?
AGENT MORETTI CALLED,
SAYS THEY WANT YOU
TO HELP I.D. A SUSPECT.
[ SIGHS ]
ALL RIGHT. GET THE CAR.
I'LL GET MY COAT.
Man: [ Slavic accent ]
HELLO, DR. PIERCE.
MAY I HELP YOU?
MAYBE I CAN HELP YOU,
PROFESSOR.
FRIENDLY ADVICE --
WON'T COST YOU NOTHING.
IT'S BETTER FOR EVERYONE --
YOU, ESPECIALLY --
IF YOU DON'T HELP FBI
ON THIS CASE NO MORE.
[ SCOFFS ]
HOW DO YOU KNOW I'M...
WE HAVE MANY FRIENDS,
EVEN AT FBI.
YOU HAVE A MOLE.
[ CHUCKLES ]
A MOLE.
WE'RE NOT KGB,
BUT, YES...
I SUPPOSE
YOU COULD SAY THIS.
I HEAR YOU ARE
A VERY SMART MAN, PROFESSOR.
SO I THINK YOU KNOW
IT IS NOT HEALTHY
FOR YOU TO WORK
WITH THESE PEOPLE.
AFTER ALL, YOU DON'T WANT
TO ALSO DISAPPEAR, DO YOU?
[ DOOR OPENS, CLOSES ]
DO ANY OF THESE MEN
REMIND YOU OF THE MAN
WHO THREATENED
TO HURT YOUR WIFE?
ANYTHING STAND OUT?
HANDS, HAIRLINE, POSTURE?
NUMBER 2.
WHY HIM?
I RECOGNIZE
THAT WIDOW'S PEAK,
THOSE SCRAWNY,
BOWED LEGS.
I WANT THAT [BLEEP] TO PAY
FOR WHAT HE DID TO MY WIFE.
Kate: THAT'S GOOD. IT'S THE SAME
GUY WHOSE VOICE YOU I.D.'d.
DANIEL, CAN YOU TESTIFY IN COURT
THAT THE VISUAL I.D. IS VALID
DESPITE MR. PRENTICE'S
CONDITION?
DANIEL. YES OR NO?
IS THE I.D. SOLID?
YES, I -- I'LL STAND BY IT.
I'M GONNA LAY IT OUT
FOR YOU, YURI.
YOU GOT PRIORS --
PIMPING, EXTORTION, ASSAULT.
FRANK PRENTICE
JUST FINGERED YOU
AS THE MAN WHO THREATENED
TO ABDUCT HIS WIFE.
SHE DISAPPEARED.
NOW SHE'S DEAD.
WHAT DO YOU MAKE?
$40,000, $45,000 A YEAR?
YOU'RE A HOT
LITTLE SPINNER.
COME WORK FOR ME.
YOU COULD EARN SOME REAL MONEY.
AN INNOCENT GIRL
WAS KILLED, YURI.
NOW, IN ADDITION TO THE FACT
THAT IT REALLY [BLEEP] ME OFF,
IT'S ALSO MURDER DURING
THE COMMISSION OF A FELONY.
DO YOU KNOW
WHAT THAT MEANS?
DEATH PENALTY.
AND I FOR ONE AM NOT GONNA
BE CRYING AT YOUR FUNERAL.
BUT MAYBE...
YOU DIDN'T
MEAN TO KILL HER.
YEAH, THE MEDICAL
EXAMINER SAYS
THAT SHE DIED FROM A BLOW
TO THE BASE OF THE SKULL.
MAYBE SHE WAS
TRYING TO GET AWAY.
MAYBE SHE FELL,
HIT HER HEAD.
NOW YOU'RE ONLY LOOKING
AT INVOLUNTARY MANSLAUGHTER.
YOU MIGHT ONLY DO
18 MONTHS.
YOU'RE OFFERING ME A DEAL,
JUST 'CAUSE YOU'RE SWEET ON ME?
YOU'RE TOO SMALL
FOR ME, YURI --
IN MORE WAYS THAN ONE,
I WOULD BET.
[ SCOFFS ]
NO, I WANT
SOMETHING BIGGER.
I WANT ALEXEI TUPELOV.
OH. [ CHUCKLES ]
[BLEEP]
WHAT ARE YOU SMOKING?
I RAT OUT TUPELOV, I MIGHT
AS WELL GET THE DEATH PENALTY.
OKAY.
WE'VE ALREADY GOT YOU
ON THE EXTORTION.
IT'S UP TO FIVE YEARS
FOR EACH COUNT.
I HOPE YOU ENJOY
YOUR STAY AT MARION.
Roger: DO YOU THINK
HE'S GONNA GIVE US TUPELOV?
IT WOULD HELP IF WE COULD
CONNECT HIM TO THE CRIME SCENE.
ANY LUCK
ON THE BLUE CAMARO?
YURI DRIVES AN [ SIGHS ]
I DOUBT YURI AND HIS BOYS
WOULD BE STUPID ENOUGH
TO COMMIT KIDNAPPING
IN A REGISTERED CAR.
[ CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYS ]
EVERYTHING ALL RIGHT,
DR. PIERCE?
YES, I'M FINE.
THAT PENDANT.
YURI PETROVICH
HAS ONE JUST LIKE IT.
WELL, I GREW UP WITH A LOT
OF THE GUYS IN TUPELOV'S CREW.
THAT'S WHY I WAS PICKED
FOR THE TASK FORCE.
SO, WHAT DO YOU THINK?
DID YURI
REALLY KILL OLENA?
WHO ELSE
COULD HAVE DONE IT?
WELL, LET'S JUST SAY
SOME FRIENDS OF MINE
WOULD BE VERY GRATEFUL
IF YOU DIDN'T HELP MORETTI
PIN THIS MURDER ON YURI.
YOU'RE THE MOLE.
NO. NOT ME, PROFESSOR.
BUT YOU'RE RIGHT.
THERE IS A MOLE.
WHO?
DANIEL.
GIVE YOU A LIFT BACK?
YEAH.
SURE..
Natalie: YOU'RE BEING THREATENED
BY A RUSSIAN MOBSTER,
AND YOU DON'T BOTHER
MENTIONING IT TO KATE?
WHY NOT?
'CAUSE HE'S PROBABLY
A [BLEEP] HALLUCINATION --
THE SAME AS THE LADY AGENT
TURNED OUT TO BE.
I JUST -- I DON'T WANT KATE
TO THINK I'M BONKERS.
WELL, IF YOU'RE SO CONVINCED
THAT HE WASN'T REAL,
why do you keep looking
out the window?!
Because I might be wrong!
W-what if there really is
a goon out there
waiting to break
my kneecaps?
DANIEL, YOU AND I BOTH KNOW
THAT FEELING THREATENED
BY A CRIMINAL CONSPIRACY
STRAIGHT OUT OF A SPY NOVEL
IS CLASSIC
SCHIZOPHRENIC DELUSION.
WHAT'S MORE PLAUSIBLE --
THAT THERE'S A FIENDISH PLOT
WITH MOBSTERS
AND CORRUPT FBI AGENTS
OR THAT YOU'RE
IMAGINING IT?
THANK YOU
FOR BEING HERE.
THAT'S WHAT FRIENDS
ARE FOR.
YOU SAID THIS THUG TOLD YOU
THAT IT WASN'T HEALTHY
FOR YOU TO KEEP WORKING
FOR THE FBI.
IT SOUNDS LIKE A MANIFESTATION
OF YOUR ANXIETY
ABOUT GETTING INVOLVED
WITH THESE CASES,
BECAUSE YOU KNOW
THEY GET YOU OFF YOUR ROUTINE
AND TRIGGER EPISODES.
HE ALSO SAID I MIGHT DISAPPEAR.
WHAT'S THAT ABOUT?
LAST TIME YOU
CHECKED INTO REXFORD,
YOU DIDN'T TELL ANYBODY
WHERE YOU WERE --
YOUR FRIENDS,
YOUR STUDENTS.
YOU JUST DISAPPEARED
OUT OF THEIR LIVES.
SO, I'M NOT AFRAID
OF UKRAINIAN GANGSTERS
SO MUCH AS ORDERLIES
WITH BUTTERFLY NETS?
YOU'RE NOT GOING BACK
TO THE HOSPITAL.
YOU HAVE ME,
YOU HAVE LEWICKI,
AND YOU'RE MANAGING
YOUR CONDITION.
[ SIGHS ]
SOME DAYS I MANAGE
BETTER THAN OTHERS.
YOUR SYMPTOMS ARE MORE ACUTE
WHEN YOUR SUBCONSCIOUS
IS WORKING ON A PROBLEM
THAT IT CAN'T QUITE SOLVE.
THE UKRAINIAN GUY
SAID THERE WAS A MOLE.
NOW, IT'S NOT THE AGENT,
OBVIOUSLY.
WELL, MAYBE IT'S A RIDDLE.
WHAT'S A MOLE?
A SPY, AN IMPOSTER, SOMEONE
WHO HIDES IN PLAIN SIGHT.
BUT THERE'S
ANOTHER KIND OF MOLE --
THE KIND THAT BURROWS
UNDERGROUND.
MOLES ARE BLIND.
[ KNOCK ON DOOR ]
DO YOU KNOW
WHAT TIME IT IS?
YURI DIDN'T KILL
OLENA PRENTICE.
WHAT?
YOU WOKE ME UP AT...
3:18 A.M.
TO ACCUSE ME
OF TRYING TO COERCE A CONFESSION
OUT OF AN INNOCENT MAN?
THAT SCUMBAG
IS ANYTHING BUT INNOCENT,
BUT THAT DOES NOT MAKE HIM
THE KILLER.
OKAY, DANIEL.
IF THE LYING, PIMPING,
SADISTIC FELON
WHO THREATENED TO ABDUCT OLENA
DIDN'T KILL HER, THEN WHO DID?
HER HUSBAND.
HE PASSED A POLYGRAPH.
HE'S FACE-BLIND!
FOR ALL WE KNOW, HE --
HE KILLED HIS OWN WIFE
WITHOUT REALIZING IT WAS HER.
BUT YOU JUST PROVED THAT
PROSOPAGNOSIACS CAN I.D. PEOPLE
BY THEIR VOICE OR THEIR POSTURE
OR WHATEVER.
HE WOULD HAVE KNOWN
HIS OWN WIFE.
MAYBE SHE WAS WEARING
SOME KIND OF DISGUISE.
[ Laughing ] WHAT IS THIS?
IS THIS, LIKE, A SPY NOVEL?
DON'T -- I'M JUST...
I'M JUST SAYING --
I'M JUST SAYING IT'S POSSIBLE.
OKAY, DANIEL.
WHY WOULD OLENA
HAVE BEEN WEARING A DISGUISE?
I DON'T KNOW. MAYBE SHE
WAS TRYING TO GET AWAY FROM HIM.
YOU SAID YOURSELF
HOW AWFUL HE IS.
THE MARRIAGE BROKER DID SAY
THAT SHE WANTED OUT.
YOU SEE? YOU SEE?
SO SHE RUNS AWAY.
FRANK REALIZES THAT -- THAT
HIS PRIZED POSSESSION IS GONE,
AFTER ALL THE DEBT HE'S RUN UP
AND THREATS HE'S ENDURED
FROM YURI --
ALL OF IT FOR HER.
SO HE TRACKS THE UNGRATEFUL
[BLEEP] DOWN, AND HE KILLS HER.
EXCEPT THERE'S A FLAW
IN YOUR THEORY.
IF FRANK KILLED HIS WIFE FOR THE
REASONS THAT YOU JUST LAID OUT,
HE WOULD HAVE KNOWN THAT IT WAS
HER WHO HE WAS KILLING,
AND HE WOULDN'T HAVE PASSED
A POLY, FACE-BLIND OR NOT.
RIGHT.
SO, UH, FRANK THOUGHT
SHE WAS KIDNAPPED,
SO MAYBE HE DIDN'T REALIZE
THAT SHE'D RUN AWAY
UNTIL AFTER
HE TOOK THE POLYGRAPH.
THEN -- THEN
HE FIGURES OUT THE TRUTH,
AND HE TRACKS HER DOWN,
AND HE KILLS HER.
NICE.
EXCEPT THE MEDICAL EXAMINER
PUTS HER TIME OF DEATH
BEFORE HE TOOK THE EXAM.
OKAY.
SO -- SO -- THE -- THE --
OKAY. FORGET IT.
FORGET IT. FORGET IT.
NO, I JUST -- YOU KNOW --
GO -- GO BACK TO THAT.
I'M SURE YOU'LL SLEEP THE SLEEP
OF THE JUST KNOWING THAT --
THAT THE PUZZLE'S
BEEN SOLVED
AND THAT YOU'VE NAILED
THE RIGHT GUY FOR THE MURDER.
WELL, I AM AWAKE ALREADY.
WELL, THEN, LET'S GO.
I'M GONNA
PUT SOME PANTS ON FIRST.
YOUR APARTMENT'S NICE.
[ KNOCK ON DOOR ]
[ Slavic accent ]
MAY I HELP YOU?
SPECIAL AGENT MORETTI, FBI.
THIS IS DR. PIERCE.
AND YOU ARE, UH, MASHA, THE
PRENTICES' HOUSEKEEPER, CORRECT?
YES.
COME IN.
SO, YOU'RE THE ONE WHO FOUND
MR. PRENTICE UNCONSCIOUS?
YES.
COME HOME FROM MOVIES.
SEE HIM ON FLOOR
WITH BLOOD.
FIRST I THINK
HE IS DEAD.
AND OLENA?
I CALL AMBULANCE.
THEN I LOOK FOR HER.
SHE'S NOT HERE.
I SEE
YOU'RE PACKING.
I SEND OLENA'S CLOTHES
TO HER SISTERS IN UKRAINE,
THEN I FIND OTHER JOB.
YOU WON'T BE STAYING ON
WITH MR. PRENTICE?
OLENA SPEAK LITTLE ENGLISH.
THEY HIRE ME SO I TRANSLATE.
NOW SHE'S GONE.
OLENA DIDN'T HAVE ANY FAMILY
HERE IN THE STATES?
SHE HAVE COUSIN --
PAULINA.
SHE COME HERE TO VISIT
BEFORE I WORK HERE,
BUT MR. PRENTICE NOT LIKE HER,
TELL HER TO GO AWAY.
DOESN'T SOUND LIKE OLENA WAS
VERY HAPPY WITH MR. PRENTICE.
MR. PRENTICE
NOT LET HER GO ANYWHERE.
HE SAY IT IS NOT SAFE, BUT
HE WORK ALWAYS UNTIL VERY LATE.
UNTIL I COME,
OLENA WAS ALONE.
DID HE EVER HURT HER?
SOMETIMES HE HIT HER.
DO YOU THINK IT'S POSSIBLE
SHE WASN'T KIDNAPPED --
THAT MAYBE SHE RAN AWAY?
BUT...
THERE WAS UKRAINIAN MAN ARRESTED
FOR HER MURDER, NO?
DANIEL.
"THANKS FOR
TAKING CARE OF THIS, BABY.
HUGS AND KISSES.
JOLENE."
WHO'S JOLENE?
I NEVER HEAR THIS NAME.
WELL, WHOEVER SHE IS, FRANK'S
PAYING HER CREDIT-CARD BILLS.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
JOLENE GREY?
I'M SPECIAL AGENT MORETTI.
THIS IS DR. DANIEL PIERCE.
THANK YOU FOR AGREEING
TO COME TALK TO US.
I'LL TELL YOU WHATEVER
YOU WANT TO KNOW,
BUT, PLEASE,
DON'T TELL MY HUSBAND.
OKAY.
YOU COOPERATE WITH US,
AND, UH, WE'LL DO WHAT WE CAN
TO KEEP THINGS DISCREET.
THANK YOU.
NOW, THIS IS SOME TAB
YOU'VE RUN UP HERE.
FANCY HOTELS, JEWELRY,
CASH ADVANCES.
I LOST MY WALLET
A FEW MONTHS AGO.
SOMEONE MUST HAVE STOLEN MY I.D.
AND OPENED THIS ACCOUNT.
YEAH, SEE,
THAT'S NOT REALLY
THE WAY IDENTITY THEFT
WORKS, JOLENE.
CRIMINALS RUN UP TABS
UNDER SOMEONE ELSE'S NAME,
AND THEN
THEY DON'T PAY THE BILL.
I'M TELLING YOU,
THESE AREN'T MY CHARGES.
MY HUSBAND TOOK AWAY
MY CREDIT CARDS LAST YEAR.
SO YOU GOT ANOTHER ONE --
PAID FOR EVERY MONTH
WITH CHECKS FROM
FRANK PRENTICE'S
BUSINESS ACCOUNT.
I DON'T KNOW
ANY FRANK PRENTICE.
I THOUGHT YOU WERE
GONNA COOPERATE, JOLENE.
NOW, ACCORDING TO
YOUR CELLPHONE RECORDS,
YOU'VE CALLED FRANK
SEVERAL TIMES A DAY
FOR THE PAST FEW MONTHS.
I'M ON A FAMILY PLAN.
MY HUSBAND PAYS THE BILL.
SO YOU GOT A SECOND PHONE,
RESERVED FOR A SPECIAL CALLER.
AFTER ALL, YOU WOULDN'T WANT
FRANK'S NUMBER
SHOWING UP
ON YOUR HUSBAND'S BILL.
OR MAYBE YOU WERE JEALOUS
OF FRANK'S WIFE.
MAYBE USED
ONE OF THOSE CASH ADVANCES
TO PAY SOMEONE TO MAKE
OLENA PRENTICE DISAPPEAR.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
CHECK OUT THOSE HEELS.
MUST HAVE COST HER
A FORTUNE.
TELL ME THE TRUTH,
JOLENE.
WHERE DID YOU GET
THOSE SHOES?
DANIEL?
THEY'RE BEAUTIFUL.
THANK YOU.
MARSHALL FIELD'S.
DID YOU PAY CASH
FOR THEM?
YES.
HOW DID YOU --
WELL, YOUR HUSBAND
TOOK YOUR CREDIT CARDS.
JOLENE, DO YOU SOMETIMES
BUY THINGS
TO MAKE YOURSELF FEEL BETTER --
CLOTHING OR JEWELRY?
[ Crying ]
I AM SO SORRY.
AND DID YOU NEED THOSE SHOES
SO BADLY
THAT YOU STOLE MONEY
TO BUY THEM?
YES.
I THOUGHT THAT'S
WHAT THIS WAS ABOUT.
I'LL PAY BACK EVERY PENNY.
PLEASE.
DON'T TELL MY HUSBAND.
COMPULSIVE BUYING
DISORDER.
Roger: ONE OF OUR AGENTS SHOWED
JOLENE'S PHOTO TO THE DESK CLERK
AT THE HOTEL
WHERE THE GOLD CARD WAS USED.
SAID HE'S NEVER
SEEN HER BEFORE.
BUT A DIFFERENT WOMAN
CHECKED IN REGULARLY
USING JOLENE'S NAME,
MET FRANK THERE.
BOTH WOMEN HAVE BLACK HAIR,
BUT ACCORDING TO THE DESK CLERK,
THE OTHER ONE IS
"WAY HOTTER."
I WAS RIGHT THE FIRST TIME.
"MOLE" MEANS "IMPOSTER."
WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
MAYBE THIS IMPOSTER GOT HERSELF
A WIG OR A DYE JOB,
DID SOMETHING
TO MAKE HERSELF LOOK
ENOUGH LIKE JOLENE'S
DRIVER'S-LICENSE PHOTO
TO FOOL ANYONE WHO DIDN'T
LOOK TOO CLOSELY.
SHE MADE CHARGES EVERY
TUESDAY AND THURSDAY LAST MONTH
AT A PLACE
CALLED THE RED RABBLE.
THAT'S A BAR OFF I-90.
AND TODAY'S THURSDAY.
[ ROCK MUSIC PLAYS IN DISTANCE ]
THAT'S RIGHT, PROFESSOR.
I'M FOLLOWING YOU.
HOW DO YOU LIKE
MY NEW AMERICAN CAR?
Kate: DANIEL?
WHAT'S GOING ON?
LOOK.
A BLUE CAMARO.
THE SAME TYPE OF CAR
PARKED OUTSIDE OF OLENA'S
THE NIGHT SHE DISAPPEARED.
EXCUSE ME!
HI, EVERYBODY!
LISTEN, I...
WAS BACKING UP
IN THE PARKING LOT,
AND I KIND OF SORT OF HIT
A BLUE CAMARO.
SO WHOSEVER CAR THAT IS,
I WILL TOTALLY PAY FOR
THE DAMAGE, AND I AM SO SORRY.
YEAH, THAT'S MY CAR.
HOW BAD IS IT?
IT'S PRETTY BAD.
[ CHUCKLES ]
FBI.
YOU'RE UNDER ARREST.
[ PATRONS MURMURING ]
I WAS THERE,
BUT I DIDN'T KILL OLENA.
I LOVED HER.
I GOT A SIDE GIG
INSTALLING SATELLITE DISHES.
IT PAYS FOR MY MUSIC.
A COUPLE MONTHS AGO, I PUT IN
A DISH AT OLENA'S HOUSE.
SHE WAS LONELY.
WE TALKED AND STARTED
SEEING EACH OTHER.
SHE WOULD NEVER
SPEND THE NIGHT.
SHE ALWAYS HAD TO GET HOME
BEFORE FRANK DID.
SHE TOLD ME THAT SHE WAS
GONNA LEAVE HIM.
WELL, MAYBE YOU REALIZED
THAT WAS NEVER GONNA HAPPEN,
SO YOU GOT ANGRY
AND YOU KILLED HER.
NO! NO, SHE WAS SUPPOSED TO
COME OVER AND NEVER SHOWED.
SHE DIDN'T
PICK UP HER PHONE.
I GOT SCARED THAT FRANK
MAYBE FOUND OUT ABOUT US
AND MAYBE HE HURT HER.
I DROVE OVER.
NO ONE ANSWERED THE DOOR,
SO I BROKE IN.
BUT OLENA WASN'T THERE.
AND THEN FRANK CAME IN.
AND HE TURNED ON
THE LIGHTS.
HE RUSHED ME, SO I GRABBED
A LAMP AND I HIT HIM.
AND THEN
I GOT THE [BLEEP] OUT OF THERE.
THAT'S A VERY COMPELLING
STORY, JAKE,
EXCEPT IT DOESN'T EXPLAIN
ONE THING.
HOW DOES JOLENE GREY
FIT IN?
WHO?
SUPER-HOTTIE,
BLACK HAIR.
COMES TO SEE YOU PLAY
EVERY THURSDAY NIGHT
AT THE RED RABBLE.
LOTS OF PEOPLE
COME TO HEAR US.
ARE YOU THINKING
WHAT I'M THINKING?
EXCEPT JOLENE
WAS HAVING AN AFFAIR
WITH OLENA'S HUSBAND,
FRANK.
NOW, IT CANNOT JUST BE
A COINCIDENCE.
I BET YOU KNOW
WHO THE MOLE IS NOW.
I DON'T KNOW
ANY JOLENE GREY.
ACTUALLY, YOU DO.
YOU -- YOU KNOW HER
INTIMATELY.
Kate: MR. PRENTICE, CAN YOU
HELP US I.D. THIS WOMAN?
Frank: NO. WHO IS SHE?
THERE ANYTHING ABOUT HER
THAT'S FAMILIAR TO YOU?
HER HAIR, MAYBE?
NO.
WHY -- WHY WOULD I --
YOU'VE BEEN HAVING AN AFFAIR
WITH THIS WOMAN FOR MONTHS.
[ CHUCKLES ]
THAT'S [BLEEP]
WELL, MAYBE HER NAME WILL
RING A BELL -- JOLENE GREY?
NO. I-I DON'T KNOW.
YOU'VE BEEN PAYING OFF
HER CREDIT CARDS.
WE HAVE THE RECORDS.
OKAY, SO I BOUGHT JOLENE
SOME NICE STUFF.
WHAT? ARE YOU SAYING
SOMEBODY KILLED HER?
ACTUALLY, THE REAL JOLENE GREY
IS VERY MUCH ALIVE.
YEAH, SHE LIVES OUT
IN THE 'BURBS WITH HER FAMILY.
THIS WOMAN
STOLE HER IDENTITY.
SHE WORE A WIG TO MAKE SURE
YOU WOULDN'T RECOGNIZE HER --
VERY MUCH LIKE THIS ONE.
I'LL BET
YOU RECOGNIZE HER NOW.
YOU PUT A WIG ON A CORPSE?
WHAT KIND OF SICK --
THAT'S OLENA.
YOU WERE HAVING AN AFFAIR
WITH YOUR OWN WIFE, FRANK.
THAT'S NOT POSSIBLE.
ACTUALLY, IT IS.
OLENA MUST HAVE FIGURED OUT OVER
TIME THAT YOU WERE FACE-BLIND,
SO SHE STOLE ANOTHER WOMAN'S
IDENTITY AND SEDUCED YOU.
SHE WAS PRACTICALLY
A PRISONER IN YOUR HOME,
SO SHE USED YOUR CONDITION
AGAINST YOU
TO BILK YOU
FOR CASH, JEWELS.
I THINK SHE WAS PROBABLY
TRYING TO SAVE UP ENOUGH MONEY
TO GET AWAY FROM YOU,
BUT, UH, TURNS OUT
YOU WEREN'T THE ONLY ONE
SHE WAS SCREWING.
WHAT?
YEAH, TURNS OUT
WHILE YOU WERE AWAY AT WORK,
SHE WAS BANGING THE GUY WHO
INSTALLED YOUR SATELLITE DISH.
HE TOLD US ALL ABOUT IT.
THAT [BLEEP]
YOU CAN'T REALLY BLAME HER
FOR WANTING A BOY TOY
WHEN SHE WAS
HAVING TO SLEEP WITH YOU
AS HERSELF
AND AS JOLENE.
OLENA WAS NEVER
ABDUCTED, FRANK.
THE REASON NOBODY COULD FIND HER
IS THAT WHEN YOU KILLED
THE WOMAN YOU THOUGHT
WAS YOUR MISTRESS,
YOU'D REALLY JUST MURDERED
YOUR OWN WIFE.
T-THIS IS RIDICULOUS.
HOTEL DESK CLERK
PUTS YOU IN THE SAME ROOM AS HER
ON THE DAY OF THE MURDER.
IT WAS AN ACCIDENT.
I NEVER MEANT TO KILL HER.
TELL US WHAT HAPPENED.
MAYBE I CAN HELP YOU.
I TRIED TO END IT
WITH HER.
SHE -- SHE WAS
BLEEDING ME DRY.
I COULDN'T
AFFORD HER ANYMORE.
I TOLD HER I WAS GONNA
NEED THE JEWELRY BACK
TO PAY OFF YURI,
OR ELSE
HE WAS GONNA TAKE OLENA.
BUT JOLENE WOULDN'T LISTEN,
YOU KNOW?
NO. SAID SHE WAS NOTHING
WITHOUT ME.
THEN SHE
STARTED TO HIT ME.
I LOST IT.
WHAT ABOUT THE BODY?
I WAITED
UNTIL AFTER DARK,
TOOK HER DOWN IN
THE MAINTENANCE ELEVATOR,
AND TOSSED HER
IN THE DUMPSTER.
IT'S TOO BAD WE CAN'T CHARGE YOU
WITH TWO MURDERS.
Paul: DANIEL.
OH, HEY, PAUL.
DON'T "HEY, PAUL" ME.
YOU KNOW, YOU REALLY BLEW IT
WITH HATHAWAY.
WHY WOULD YOU WANT A FRAUD LIKE
THAT ON THE FACULTY, ANYWAY?
THAT FRAUD
IS AN ACADEMIC SUPERSTAR.
EVERYBODY WANTS HIM --
HARVARD, NORTHWESTERN --
BUT I AM GONNA GET HIM,
AND YOU'RE GONNA HELP ME DO IT.
HERE.
CUBS TICKETS.
NOW, YOU'RE GONNA APOLOGIZE
TO HATHAWAY,
AND YOU'RE GONNA INVITE HIM
TO TONIGHT'S GAME
AS A PEACE OFFERING.
COME ON, DANIEL.ILL.
I REALLY NEED YOU
TO DO THIS FOR ME.
COME ON, MAN.
YOU LOVE THE CUBBIES.
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
DANIEL.
[ SIGHS ] KATE.
HI.
[ CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY ]
FRANK PRENTICE IS TAKING A PLEA
AND COOPERATING AGAINST YURI.
THAT'S GREAT.
AND IF WE CAN GET YURI
TO ROLL ON TUPELOV,
THEN WE'LL HAVE THE UKRAINIANS
AND OLENA'S KILLER IN ONE SHOT.
DO YOU LIKE BASEBALL?
YEAH, SURE.
I MEAN, WHO DOESN'T LIKE
A COLD BEER AND A HOT DOG
AT A BALLGAME, RIGHT?
WELL, I-I, UH,
JUST HAPPEN TO HAVE
TWO, UH, TWO TICKETS
TO THE CUBS GAME TONIGHT.
THAT SOUNDS GREAT.
WHAT TIME?
[ CROWD CHEERING ]
[ OVERLAPPING VOICES ]
HAVE FUN.
WAIT, YOU'RE NOT GOING?
UH, NO.
CROWDS DRIVE ME CRAZY.
AH.
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
THANKS.
ARE YOU STALKING ME?
OH, MY GOD.
[ BOTH CHUCKLHI.
I COULD ASK YOU
THE SAME QUESTION.
LAST CHANCE
TO BUY ME THAT DRINK.
I LEAVE TOWN TOMORROW.
UH, YOU KNOW, I'M SORRY.
I DON'T THINK I CAN.
I HAVE PLANS.
BUT TRAVEL SAFE.
ACTUALLY, UM...
DO YOU LIKE BASEBALL?
Natalie:
WHY DIDN'T YOU TAKE KATE?
BECAUSE I'D RATHER
WATCH IT ON TV...
WITH YOU.
SOMETHING'S BOTHERING YOU.
IT'S OLENA.
I JUST --
I CAN'T FIGURE OUT
HOW A YOUNG GIRL
WHO BARELY SPOKE ENGLISH
PULLED OFF
SUCH A COMPLICATED SCAM.
I GUESS
SHE HAD EVERYONE FOOLED.
Man: FOUL BALL
DOWN THE THIRD-BASE SIDE.
OUT OF PLAY.
WHOA.
GREAT CATCH BY THAT FAN.
OH, I DON'T BELIEVE IT.
SHE TOOK THAT [BLEEP]
AND HE CATCHES
A FOUL BALL.
YOU KNOW HOW MANY GAMES
I WENT TO AS A KID,
AND I NEVER ONCE
CAUGHT A FOUL BALL?
DANIEL, YOU HAVE NO ONE
TO BLAME BUT YOURSELF.
THAT COULD HAVE BEEN YOU.
BUT INSTEAD,
YOU LET HIM TAKE YOUR PLACE.
SHE TOOK HER PLACE.
THERE'S ANOTHER MOLE.
WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
WHO ARE YOU CALLING?
KATE.
ARE YOU TRYING TO RUIN
HER DATE?
[ BUTTONS CLICKING ]
I'M GONNA TELL HER
OLENA ISN'T DEAD.
YOU TAKING EVERYTHING?
MRS. PRENTICE IS DEAD, AND
MR. PRENTICE GO TO JAIL, SO --
IT'S OKAY. NO ONE'S
ACCUSING YOU OF STEALING.
IT ALL BELONGS TO YOU,
ANYWAY, DOESN'T IT...
...OLENA?
LISTEN,
FRANK PRENTICE IS A PIG.
WE DON'T BLAME YOU
FOR WANTING TO MAKE HIM PAY.
WHAT WE COULDN'T FIGURE
OUT WAS HOW YOU DID
IT ALL ON YOUR OWN.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE TALKING --
I REMEMBERED YOU MENTIONED
A COUSIN THAT FRANK
DIDN'T LIKE -- PAULINA.
EVER SINCE WE WERE LITTLE GIRLS
IN UKRAINE, PAULINA PROTECT ME.
AND NOW SHE PROTECTED YOU
FROM FRANK.
SHE MARRIED AMERICAN, TOO,
FIVE YEARS BEFORE,
BUT SHE DIVORCE HIM,
STAY IN COUNTRY.
I CALL HER,
ASK HER TO COME.
IT WAS SO GOOD TO SEE HER.
SHE STAYED FOR A FEW DAYS.
BUT SOON WE NOTICE
SOMETHING STRANGE.
MY HUSBAND SOMETIMES --
HE THINK PAULINA IS ME.
WHEN NEXT TIME SHE COME
TO VISIT, HE NOT RECOGNIZE HER,
EVEN THOUGH HE KNOW HER.
THAT'S WHEN SHE REALIZED
HE WAS FACE-BLIND.
AND SHE MAKE PLAN
TO GET HIS MONEY.
BUT FIRST SHE NEED NEW NAME
SO HE DOESN'T GET SUSPICIOUS.
SO SHE STEAL WALLET AT MALL,
AND SHE MAKE HERSELF LOOK LIKE
WOMAN ON DRIVING LICENSE.
HE'S NOT USED TO BEAUTIFUL WOMAN
PAYING ATTENTION TO HIM,
SO HE GIVE HER MONEY, JEWELS,
ANYTHING SHE WANT.
FOR ME, IT GET WORSE.
I WANT TO RUN AWAY.
BUT PAULINA SAY WE HAVE TO WAIT
UNTIL WE GET ALL FRANK'S MONEY
AND THAT SHE HAVE NEW PLAN
TO PROTECT ME.
I GIVE HER HAIRCUT, AND I GIVE
HER MY CLOTHES AND MY PERFUME.
PAULINA IS STRONGER THAN ME.
SHE MAKE FRANK
STOP HITTING HER...
...AND SHE CONVINCE FRANK
TO HIRE UKRAINIAN MAID
TO KEEP HER COMPANY.
SO PAULINA
BECAME YOU AND JOLENE,
AND YOU BECAME THE MAID.
IT'S AN INGENIOUS PLAN.
YOU ARE
GOING TO ARREST ME.
YOU'RE AN ACCESSORY
TO FRAUD.
THE U.S. ATTORNEY'S OFFICE
MIGHT WANT TO CHARGE YOU,
BUT I'LL DO MY BEST
TO CONVINCE THEM
THAT BEING MARRIED
TO AN ABUSIVE, CHEATING MURDERER
WAS PROBABLY
PUNISHMENT ENOUGH.
THANK YOU.
BUT MY HUSBAND WILL FIND OUT
WHAT WE DID TO HIM,
AND WHEN HE LEAVE PRISON,
HE WILL FIND ME,
AND WITHOUT PAULINA --
YOU WERE THREATENED
BY A KNOWN ASSOCIATE
OF THE TUPELOV ORGANIZATION.
I CAN MAKE
A PRETTY GOOD CASE
THAT YOU BELONG
IN WITNESS PROTECTION.
YOU'LL GET A FRESH START, OLENA.
NEW NAME, NEW LIFE.
Paul: DANIEL!
PAUL, LOOK,
I KNOW YOU'RE UPSET.
UPSET? NO, NO, NO.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU SAID TO HATHAWAY,
BUT SUDDENLY
HE IS IN LOVE WITH THIS TOWN.
HE'S TAKING THE JOB.
YOU DID GOOD, BUDDY.
Daniel: WALT WHITMAN WROTE,
"I CONTAIN MULTITUDES."
TURNS OUT HE WAS MORE RIGHT
THAN HE KNEW.
THE SELF IS REALLY A COLLECTION
OF SEVERAL
DISTINCT NEURAL NETWORKS,
ALL RUNNING ON THIS GLOB
OF JELLY BETWEEN OUR EARS.
SO, IF THERE ARE DIFFERENT
VERSIONS OF YOURSELF
FLOATING AROUND
INSIDE YOUR SKULL,
WHICH ONE IS THE REAL YOU?
ARE YOU THE LEAD GUITARIST,
ROCKING OUT ONCE A WEEK?
OR IS IT YOUR 9:00-TO-5:00
THAT TRULY DEFINES YOU?
CAN ONE OF THOSE SELVES
BE A DEVOTED SPOUSE...
...AND THE OTHER A LYING,
THIEVING, OUT-OF-CONTROL ADDICT?
CAN YOU LONG FOR LOVE
AND YET STILL BE CURSED
BY GENETICS AND THE ENVIRONMENT
AND REMAIN THE SAME SON
OF A [BLEEP] YOU'VE ALWAYS BEEN?
AND EVEN IF YOU DO CHANGE
SOMETHING ABOUT YOURSELF...
...YOUR FACE...
YOUR NAME...
WHERE YOU LIVE...
...CAN YOU EVER ACTUALLY CHANGE
WHO YOU REALLY ARE?